bvdinfo.com 2019-10-29

# Privacy Policy | Bureau van Dijk

This Privacy Policy explains how we collect your Personal Data (defined below) on those web sites of Bureau van Dijk and its service providers that post or link directly to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the "Site") and through offline means, how we use, disclose, and protect such data, and the choices you have concerning our use of such data. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. Bureau van Dijk may from time to time update this Privacy Policy. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will become effective when we post or link to the revised Privacy Policy on the Site. Please review the “Last Updated” legend at the top of this page to determine when this Privacy Policy was most recently revised.

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, "Bureau van Dijk", "we", "us", and "our" means the Bureau van Dijk group of companies but shall also include Bureau van Dijk's, parent company, the Moody's Corporation including Moody's Investors Service, Inc., Moody’s Analytics, Inc. and their affiliates. A complete list of Moody’s group affiliates including the Bureau van Dijk group of companies can be found in the latest Moody’s 10-K filing to the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission ("SEC"), available at <http://ir.moodys.com/news-and-financials/sec-filings/default.aspx>. 

You do not have to provide us with any Personal Data to visit the Site. However, if you choose to withhold requested information, you may not be able to visit all sections or use all features of the Site.

This Privacy Policy shall also apply to any Bureau van Dijk mobile application and other forms of Bureau van Dijk online activity that reference this Privacy Policy. In such instances, the term "Site" shall include the applicable mobile application or other Bureau van Dijk’s online activity whenever that term is used herein. In connection with your use of any Bureau van Dijk mobile application, your Personal Data (and Other Data, as described below) may also be collected and used by your mobile device manufacturer, the mobile application store from which you obtained the Bureau van Dijk mobile application, your telecommunication provider, or other third parties involved in the delivery of the application or data to your mobile device, and such collection and use shall be subject to the privacy policy of the applicable third party. Bureau van Dijk is not responsible for any third party’s privacy practices.

### Types of Data Collected

We gather Personal Data and Other Data (as described below).

### Collection of Personal Data

Personal data is information that identifies you or can be used to identify or contact you, e.g., your name, email address, address, or phone number ("Personal Data"). We may need to collect and process Personal Data in order to provide requested information, products or services to you (including the Site) or because we are legally required to do so.

  * Bureau van Dijk requests Personal Data from you if the Site requires registration. The registration process requests that you provide your name, business email address, business address, business phone number, and company affiliation, and agree to the User Agreement presented at the time of registration.
  * Bureau van Dijk may receive Personal Data from social media platforms. For example, if you elect to use your social media credentials to log-in to your Site account, certain Personal Data from your social media account will be shared with us, which may include Personal Data that is part of your social media profile. 
  * Bureau van Dijk may collect Personal Data voluntarily provided by you, including in emails to the Site, online forms, order and registration forms, surveys, promotion participation, phone calls and online chats with Bureau van Dijk customer service and through other means. 
  * On some of Bureau van Dijk Sites you may be able to maintain "portfolios," where, if you are a registered user, you have the option to list financial instruments in which you have a special interest. To be useful, this information must be stored on the Site, and is accessible to anyone with whom you share your username and password. For this reason, please safeguard your username and password carefully and do not disclose it to any other person.
  * We may use third-party payment services (each, a "Payment Service") to collect payments made through the Site. If you wish to make a payment through the Site, you may be directed to a webpage that is hosted by the Payment Service (or the Payment Service's service providers) and not by Bureau van Dijk. Any Personal Data that you provide through a Payment Service page will be collected by Payment Service and not by Bureau van Dijk, and will be subject to Payment Service's privacy policy, rather than this Privacy Policy. Bureau van Dijk has no control over, and is not responsible for, Payment Service's use of information collected through the Payment Service page.
  * Bureau van Dijk collects information through various other means, including participation at conferences and events, individual introductions, from employers that enroll their employees in our services, and from selected third-party business partners.

###  Use of Personal Data Collected

We use Personal Data for _legitimate business purposes_ , including the following:

  * Fulfillment of Requests. Bureau van Dijk may use Personal Data about you to deliver products and services to you, and provide you with information about products and services you’ve ordered. We will engage in these activities to manage our contractual relationship with you and/or to comply with a legal obligation.
  * Other Communications. From time to time, we may use Personal Data about you to inform you of products, programs, services and promotions that we believe may be of interest to you. If your employer is a Bureau van Dijk customer, we may also inform you of such products, programs, services and promotions using Personal Data about you that your employer provided to Bureau van Dijk. If you would prefer that we not send electronic marketing messages to you, please see the _"Your Choices"_ section below. 
  * Promotions. We may operate sweepstakes, contests and similar promotions (collectively, "Promotions"). If you choose to enter Bureau van Dijk Promotions, we typically ask you for certain Personal Data when you enter and, if applicable, win a Promotion. You should carefully review the rules of each Promotion in which you participate, as they may contain additional important information about our use of Personal Data about you. To the extent that the terms and conditions of such rules concerning the treatment of your Personal Data conflict with this Privacy Policy, the terms and conditions of such rules shall control. We use this information to operate the Promotions.
  * Other Business Purposes. We may also use Personal Data about you for other business purposes, such as data analysis (for example, to improve the efficiency of our services), editorial and feedback purposes, providing customer support, customizing and improving the content and layout of the Site, completing business transactions (for example, to confirm content requested is received by customers), development of marketing and promotion plans and materials, statistical analysis of user behavior (for example, to understand what parts of the Site are of most interest to users), product development, market research, administering individual accounts, and meeting government regulatory requirements such as sales tax collection, audits, etc. We may also use Personal Data of journalist/media contacts for press release distribution or sharing other newsworthy developments related to our business activities. We engage in these activities to manage our contractual relationship with you, to comply with a legal obligation, and/or because we have a legitimate interest.
  * Administrative Communications. Bureau van Dijk reserves the right to use Personal Data to send to you important information regarding the Site, products, services, your account status, changes to the User Agreement, this Privacy Policy, or any other policies, agreements or transactions relevant to your use of the Site, products and/or services. Because this information may be important to your use of the Site, products and/or services, you may not opt-out of receiving such communications. We will engage in this activity to manage our contractual relationship with you and/or to comply with a legal obligation.

### Collection and Use of Other Data

_We and our service providers may also collect and use the following types of data, referred to in this Privacy Policy as “Other Data”:  
_

  * Monitoring Data. Bureau van Dijk and its service providers may collect and/or track other information such as demographic information, domain names, computer type, browser types, screen resolution, and other statistical data involving the use of the Site ("Monitoring Data"). We use Monitoring Data to help us understand who uses the Site and to improve and market it, as well as our other web sites and services.  
Unless combined with Personal Data, Monitoring Data does not personally identify you or any other user, and we may use it for any purpose. 
  * Aggregated Data. We may aggregate Personal Data in a manner such that the end-product does not personally identify you or any other user of the Site, for example, by using information to calculate the percentage of our users who have a particular telephone area code. Such aggregate information may also be used for any purpose.
  * Cookies. To enhance the Internet experience on the Site, Bureau van Dijk and our service providers may use ‘cookies’ on the Site. Cookies are data that a web server transfers to an individual's computer for recordkeeping and other purposes. We use cookies and other technologies to facilitate users' ongoing access to and use of our Site. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to automatically decline cookies, or to be given the choice of declining or accepting the transfer of a particular cookie, or cookies from a particular web site, to your computer. If cookies are disabled, however, all features of the Site may not operate as intended. Information about disabling cookies can be found on your Internet browser provider’s web site.   
The Site may have a Cookie Policy that applies to its use of cookies and other similar tracking technologies. If it does, then the Cookie Policy will apply in addition to this Privacy Policy.
  * Tools. We and our service providers may also use various common Internet tools such as 'pixel tags,' 'action tags,' 'web beacons,' '.gif tags,' 'JavaScript' or similar technologies (together, "Tools") in connection with Site pages and email messages in certain formats to, among other things, track the actions of Site users and email recipients, to determine the success of marketing campaigns and to compile statistics about Site usage and response rates. Tools allow us to count users who have visited certain pages of the Site, to deliver services, and to help determine the effectiveness of promotional or advertising campaigns. When used in email messages in certain formats, Tools can tell the sender whether and when the email has been opened.  
Bureau van Dijk uses cookies and Tools to understand how the Site is used and to customize and enhance the Internet experience of individual users. When you revisit the Site, Bureau van Dijk may recognize you by a Tool and customize your experience. For example, once you have completed the registration process, a cookie and/or Tool will be used to avoid having you register again. We believe cookies and Tools add value to the user experience.   
We do not respond to browser do-not-track signals at this time.
  * Google Analytics. We use Google Analytics, which uses cookies and other similar technologies, to collect and analyze information about Site use and to report on activities and trends. The service may also collect information regarding the use of other websites, apps and online resources. You can learn about Google’s practices by going to https://policies.google.com/privacy/partners, and opt out of them by downloading the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on, available at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.
  * Verification. We may use third-party services to verify that you are a human user. Any information collected as part of such verification is subject to the privacy policy of the third-party service provider.
  * IP Addresses. When you visit and interact with the Site, we and our third-party service providers may collect Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. Your IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to the computer that you are using by your Internet Service Provider (ISP). This number is identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever you visit the Site, along with the time(s) of your visit(s) and the page(s) that you visited. We use IP addresses to understand how the Site is used by our users, to improve the Site and to enhance user experience of the Site. We may also derive your approximate location from your IP address.

If we are required to treat Other Data as Personal Data under applicable law, then we may use and disclose it for the purposes described above, as well as for the purposes for which we use and disclose Personal Data as detailed in this Privacy Policy.

### Our Advertising

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve advertisements regarding products and services that may be of interest to you when you access and use the Site, our apps and other websites or online services, based on information relating to your access to and use of the Site and other websites or online services on any of your devices, as well as on information received from third parties. To do so, these companies may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser (including through the use of pixel tags). They may also use these technologies, along with information they collect about your online use, to recognize you across the devices you use, such as a mobile phone and a laptop. If you would like more information about this practice, and to learn how to opt out of it in desktop and mobile browsers on the particular device on which you are accessing this Privacy Policy, please visit <http://optout.aboutads.info/#/> and <http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#/>. You may download the AppChoices app at [www.aboutads.info/appchoices](http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices) to opt out of this practice in mobile apps. 

###  Disclosure of Personal Data Collected

_We may disclose Personal Data for the following purposes:_

  * Third-Party Service Providers. We may provide Personal Data to third-party service providers, who provide services to us, including but not limited to, data analysis, order fulfillment, payment processing, and other services. 
  * Affiliate Communications. Bureau van Dijk may transfer Personal Data among our affiliates (a list of which can be found in our parent company, Moody’s corporation latest 10-K filing to the SEC, available at <http://ir.moodys.com/news-and-financials/sec-filings/default.aspx>) to allow our affiliates to contact you regarding products, programs, services and promotions that they believe may be of interest to you, and such affiliates may otherwise use your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you would prefer not to receive marketing communications from Bureau van Dijk or our affiliates, please see the _"Your Choices"_ section below. Moody’s Corporation will be the party responsible for jointly used Personal Data.
  * Strategic Partners and Co-Branded Sites. From time to time, we may enter into a special relationship with another company that is not owned by or affiliated with Bureau van Dijk to provide or promote joint products, services, applications, or features (together, “Jointly Offered Items”). These special relationships may include co-branded web sites (“co-branded pages”). Any information, including Personal Data, that you provide in connection with one of these Jointly Offered Items, and/or on one of these co-branded pages, will be shared with our third-party partners. You should check these third parties’ web sites for information regarding their privacy practices. PLEASE NOTE THAT THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT DOES NOT ADDRESS THE PRIVACY OR INFORMATION PRACTICES OF ANY THIRD PARTIES. If you do not want Personal Data about you shared with such third parties, please do not provide Personal Data in connection with the Jointly Offered Items and/or co-branded pages.
  * Third-Party Data Providers. If you subscribe to a Bureau van Dijk product or service that contains third-party data, we may be required to provide your Personal Data to the third party as part of our reporting obligations. We will only do so if a third-party data provider conditions your receipt of their data on knowing your identity. 
  * Client Support Web Portal. If you subscribe to a document in the Content section of our Client Support Web Portal, your full name or user name will appear on the page on a subscriber list that is visible to other users. If you do not want your name or user name displayed, please do not subscribe to documents in the Content section.
  * Conferences and Events. When you attend a conference or event organized by Bureau van Dijk, your name and contact information may be shared with other attendees.
  * Promotions. We may share the Personal Data you provide in connection with Promotions with third-party sponsors of such Promotions (irrespective of whether such Promotions are hosted by us), or otherwise in accordance with the rules applicable to those Promotions. 
  * Assignment. We may disclose or transfer any and all Personal Data that we collect to an affiliated entity or a third party (and their respective advisors) in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock (including without limitation in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).
  * Law Enforcement; Emergencies; Compliance. We may use and disclose Personal Data about you to others as we believe to be appropriate: (a) in compliance with laws, rules, or regulations in any country in which Bureau van Dijk operates, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to respond to requests from government or public authorities, including government and public authorities outside your country of residence; (d) to enforce our Terms of Use; (e) to protect our operations or those of any affiliated entities; (f) to protect the rights, privacy, safety or property of Bureau van Dijk, its affiliated entities, you, or others; and (g) to permit us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain. For example, we may, to the fullest extent the law allows, disclose Personal Data about you to law enforcement agencies to assist them in identifying individuals who have been or may be engaged in unlawful activities.

### Your Choices

We give you choices regarding our use and disclosure of your Personal Data for marketing purposes. 

  * If you no longer want to receive marketing-related emails from us on a going-forward basis, you may stop receiving these marketing-related emails by sending an e-mail to privacy@bvdinfo.com [please mark your email "Unsubscribe".]
  * If you would prefer that we do not share your Personal Data on a going-forward basis with our affiliates or with unaffiliated third parties for their marketing purposes, you may cease this sharing by sending an e-mail to privacy@bvdinfo.com [please mark your e-mail “Cease Sharing”.]

We will try to comply with your request(s) as soon as reasonably practicable. Please note that if you exercise the second option as described above, we will not be able to remove your Personal Data from the databases of our affiliates or unaffiliated third parties with which we have already shared your Personal Data (i.e., to which we have already provided your Personal Data as of the date that we implement your request). Further, please note that requesting us not to share your Personal Data with affiliates or unaffiliated third parties may result in you no longer receiving any marketing emails from Bureau van Dijk and/or the Moody’s Corporation. Please also note that if you choose not to receive marketing-related messages from us, we may still send you important administrative messages, and you cannot elect to stop receiving such administrative messages, unless you choose to stop receiving services from us.

You may also indicate your choices regarding marketing-related emails by contacting us via postal mail or telephone using the “Contact Information for Bureau van Dijk” below, or if you have a Site profile/account, by changing your preferences on your Site profile/account at any time.

### How you can access, change or suppress your Personal Data

If you would like to request to review, correct, update, suppress, delete or otherwise limit our use of your Personal Data that has been previously provided to us, or if you would like to request to receive an electronic copy of your Personal Data for purposes of transmitting it to another company (to the extent this right to data portability is provided to you by applicable law), you may make a request by contacting us using the information provided in the “Contact Information for Bureau van Dijk” below. We will respond to your request consistent with applicable law. For your protection, we may only implement requests with respect to the Personal Data associated with the particular email address that you use to send us your request, and we may need to verify your identity before implementing your request. We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable and consistent with applicable law. Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes and/or to complete any transactions that you began prior to requesting the change or deletion. There may also be residual information that will remain within our databases and other records, which will not be removed.

### Links

The Site may contain links to other Internet web sites, including social media sites and third-party hosted collaboration tools. These linked sites are not under Bureau van Dijk control. We provide links only as a convenience, and Bureau van Dijk does not endorse or control, and is not responsible for, the privacy practices or the content of these linked sites. If you provide any Personal Data through any third-party web site, or choose to communicate with us using third-party collaboration tools or other social media platforms, your transaction will occur on that third party's web site (not the Site) and the Personal Data you provide will be collected by, and controlled by the privacy policy of, that third party. We recommend that you familiarize yourself with the privacy policies and practices of any such third parties. PLEASE NOTE THAT THIS PRIVACY POLICY DOES NOT ADDRESS THE PRIVACY OR INFORMATION PRACTICES OF ANY THIRD PARTIES, INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, AFFILIATED ENTITIES THAT DO NOT POST OR LINK DIRECTLY TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY.

###  Security Measures

Bureau van Dijk has established reasonable organizational and technical measures to protect Personal Data within our organization from loss, misuse, or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. Please note that while Bureau van Dijk has endeavored to create a secure and reliable Site for users, no site is 100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of any account you might have with us has been compromised), please notify us of the problem immediately by contacting us using the information provided below in "Contact Information for Bureau van Dijk" (note that if you choose to notify us via physical mail, this will delay the time it takes for us to respond to the problem).

###  Data Integrity

Bureau van Dijk will use Personal Data only in ways that are compatible with the purposes for which it was collected, authorized by this Privacy Policy, or authorized by you. Bureau van Dijk will take reasonable steps to ensure that Personal Data is relevant to its intended use, and is accurate, complete, and current (as provided by you). Bureau van Dijk depends on you to update or correct your Personal Data whenever necessary.

###  Retention Period

We will retain Personal Data about you for as long as needed or permitted in light of the purpose(s) for which it was obtained and consistent with applicable law. The criteria used to determine our retention periods include: (i) the length of time we have an ongoing relationship with you; (ii) whether there is a legal obligation to which we are subject; and (iii) whether retention is advisable in light of our legal position (such as in regard to applicable statutes of limitations, litigation or regulatory investigations). 

###  Cross Border Transfer of Personal Data

Your Personal Data may be stored and processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage service providers. In certain circumstances, courts, law enforcement agencies, regulatory agencies, or security authorities in those other countries may be entitled to access your Personal Data.

If you are located in the European Economic Area (“EEA”): Some of the non-EEA countries are recognized by the European Commission as providing an adequate level of data protection according to EEA standards (the full list of these countries is available on the EU Commission’s adequacy list online at: <https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/adequacy-protection-personal-data-non-eu-countries_en>). For transfers from the EEA to countries not considered adequate by the European Commission, we have put in place adequate measures, such as standard contractual clauses adopted by the European Commission, to protect your Personal Data. 

### Use of this Site by Minors

This Site is not directed to individuals under the age of eighteen (18), and we request that these individuals do not provide Personal Data through this Site. 

### Sensitive Personal Data

We ask that you not send us, and you not disclose, any sensitive Personal Data (e.g., social security numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion or other beliefs, health, biometrics or genetic characteristics, criminal background or trade union membership) on or through this Site or otherwise to us.

###  Contact Information for Bureau van Dijk

Questions or concerns regarding Bureau van Dijk data protection practices should be addressed to:

Chief Privacy Officer (Europe)

Bureau van Dijk Editions Electroniques SA

Avenue de Frontenex 8,1207, Geneva

E-mail: [privacy@bvdinfo.com](mailto:privacy@bvdinfo.com?subject=Privacy%20Inquiry)

If you choose to contact Bureau van Dijk via e-mail about this Privacy Policy, please mark the subject heading of your e-mail "Privacy Inquiry."

###  Additional Information for the EEA

You also may:

  * Lodge a complaint with the data protection authority for your country or region or where an alleged infringement of applicable data protection law occurs.
  * You may obtain a copy of the standard contractual clauses referenced in the “Cross Border Transfer of Personal Data” section by contacting us using the information provided in the “Contact Information for Bureau van Dijk” section.

For Germany, you also may:

Contact our German Data Protection Officer by sending an e-mail to [privacy@bvdinfo.com](mailto:privacy@bvdinfo.com?subject=German%20Inquiry) with the subject heading "German Inquiry"
